statravel.co.uk 2019-05-23

# Privacy Policy | STA Travel

Your privacy is important to us and we endeavour to maintain the privacy of registered users. Please take time to read through this Privacy Policy and our  **[Cookies Policy](https://www.statravel.co.uk/cookies-policy.htm)** , including the section on third party advertising to ensure you are aware of how we will use your Personal Information. 

**Key points to note**

• This Privacy Policy will apply to your use of our Website www.statravel.co.uk and mobile app which are operated by STA Travel Limited of Priory House, 6 Wrights Lane, London W8 6TA (“STA Travel”). It will also apply when we provide services to you in person (e.g. when you book a holiday with us at one of our stores) or otherwise engage with us.

• When you use our Website or request services from us we may collect Personal Information from you. This Privacy Policy explains what Personal Information we collect and how we will only process this information (i) to provide our services to you (ii) to comply with our legal obligations and (iii) for the purposes of our legitimate business interests (namely to analyse the use of our Website and services to continually improve our business and your customer experience).

• By continuing to use our Website or otherwise requesting services from us, you agree that we can collect, use and transfer your Personal Information as set out in this Privacy Policy.

• We will keep your Personal Information for as long as is required to provide our services to you and to comply with our legal obligations. After this period of time we will delete or anonymise your Personal Information.

• You can ask us to stop using your Personal Information at any time and have the right to ask us to delete any Personal Information that we hold about you. Just contact us at via [**this form**](https://forms-customercare.statravel.com/?division=uk#/customer_care). You can also use this form address if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy.

• Whilst we will implement appropriate security measures to protect the Personal Information that we hold, you accept the inherent security implications of disclosing Personal Information online and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless such breach has been caused by our negligence.

• Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on our Website and, where appropriate, notified to you when you next access the Website. It is your responsibility to ensure you are happy with any revised terms.

• In addition to this Privacy Policy please take the time to read our [**Cookies Policy**](https://www.statravel.co.uk/cookies-policy.htm) which will also govern your use of our Website and app.

## 1\. Company Statement

We will only use information from which you can be identified, such as your name, contact details and ID data (" **Personal Information** ") which is provided to us, or otherwise obtained by us, as set out in this Policy. We will ensure that your Personal Information is handled in accordance with the " **Data Protection Legislation** ", including (i) the UK Data Protection Act 1998, (ii) from 25 May 2018, the EU General Data Protection Regulation (which will replace the Data Protection Act 1998), (iii) the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 and (iv) all similar or related legislation relating to the processing of Personal Information and/or privacy applicable in any jurisdiction to which STA Travel has been, is or will be subject as in force at the date of this Policy or as re-enacted, applied, amended, superseded, repealed or consolidated (and in each case including any legally binding regulations, direction, and orders issued from time to time under or in connection with any such law). 

By visiting and/or contacting us in one of our stores or through the Website (or otherwise engaging with us), you acknowledge that we may collect, use and transfer your Personal Information as set out in this Policy. STA Travel reserves the right to change this Policy from time to time and you should therefore check this page frequently to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

In this Policy, " **STA Travel** ", " **we** ", " **us** " and " **our** ", refer to STA Travel Limited, registered in the United Kingdom with registered address Priory House, 6 Wrights Lane, London W8 6TA. Our company registration number is 01263330. Also, this policy applies to the websites operated in partnership with STA Experiences Ltd ([https://tours.statravel.co.uk](https://tours.statravel.co.uk/)) and International Rail ([https://rail.statravel.co.uk](https://rail.statravel.co.uk/)).

For the purposes of the Data Protection Legislation, we are deemed to be the " **data controller** " in respect of any Personal Information that you provide to us in connection with the operation of our business or we otherwise obtain about you. Where you provide us with Personal Information to be shared with a third party who will provide services directly to you (for example an airline), they shall also be a data controller of that information and you should review their own privacy policy for details as to how they handle your Personal Information.

## 2\. Personal Information that we collect from you

When you engage with us (e.g. sending us an email, using live chat, commenting on blogs, contacting us via telephone or visiting or making an enquiry through the Website or in a store), you may provide Personal Information about yourself including your name, date of birth and contact details (e.g. your address, email address and telephone number) and your job title and CV where you apply for a role with us. If you consider booking flights or a holiday with us, or requesting any other form of service from us, you may also provide us with your financial information and various other necessary Personal Information (e.g. payment details, passport numbers, visa information). 

We also have CCTV in some of our stores and offices for the purpose of crime prevention and where this is used, we will display appropriate notices.

## 3\. Technical Personal Information that we collect from you

Where you make use of our Website we may also collect technical information about your use of the Website and certain limited information about your device, your visits to our Website and when you contact our staff through the online chat help system which may be considered Personal Information. Technical Information may include: 

(a)           **Device data**. We may collect information about the type of device or platform you use (such as a computer or mobile device) to access our Website and your choice of web browser.

(b)           **Location data.** Your use of our Website may generate geographical data, such as the location or time zone of a device or IP address, which we may collect.

(c)            **Log data about your visit**. Your use of our Website automatically generates information about your unique visit which we may collect. This can include uniform resource locators (URLs), data about your internet service provider, the number and timing of clicks to and from the content on our Website; which events you view; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction data (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), email engagement rates and activities, and methods used to browse away from the page. Typically we will not be able to identify you from this information.

(d)           **Data about your interactions.** Our Website may provide you with the opportunity to interact with content in certain ways, such as by sharing content on social media. These interactions create data which we may collect, for example, the contents of a post or comment, or whether a link or image was shared using a particular social media network.

We collect some of the above information via our STA Travel Live Chat.

Some of the technical data set out above will be collected by cookies that we use on our Website. For more information on the ways in which we make use of cookies, please see our **[Cookies Policy.](https://www.statravel.co.uk/cookies-policy.htm)**

## 4\. Personal Information that we receive from other sources

We may receive information from third parties who collect Personal Information from you and pass it on to us. For example, where someone is booking a holiday on your behalf. Where this is the case, the third party is responsible for obtaining the relevant consents from you to ensure you are happy with the ways in which your Personal Information will be used.

## 5\. How we use your Personal Information

We will only use your Personal Information in order to (a) supply the products and/or services you have requested and correspond with you in relation to their provision, (b) provide support to you in respect of these services, (c) improve our Website and services, (d) comply with our own legal obligations, (e) perform internal business processes and (f) where relevant, process your application for employment. 

**Marketing Communications and Newsletters**

Where you have explicitly consented at the time we collected your Personal Information or where we otherwise have a right to do so, we may also use your Personal Information to send you our newsletters, special offers and other marketing communications, by text message, telephone and e-mail.

If it becomes apparent to us that a minor has requested marketing from us, we will stop marketing to that minor unless we have express consent from an appropriate adult.

**Opting-in to marketing communications**

When you opt-in to marketing communications we will ask you for the following personal details: email address, web tracking consent and your contact preferences. You will also be offered the opportunity to customise your email marketing communications (not compulsory). This information is then used to, where you have opted-in to such communications, (i) email you newsletters and special offers and (ii) text you marketing messages (messages sent by STA Travel will be free unless a roaming charge is made by your network operator). By opting-in to marketing communications you are agreeing to the personalised tracking of your interactions with our email marketing communications. Information collected includes but is not limited to: which emails you open and which links within the emails you click. The primary purpose of this tracking is for reporting on the performance of STA Travel’s email marketing communications. On occasion, and in the absence of a completed preference centre, we may use this data to personalise your email marketing communications. You have the ability to unsubscribe from the mailing list at any point through the unsubscribe link found in all email newsletters.

**Booking with us**

If you have booked with, or otherwise purchased products or services from us, we may send you marketing communications about similar products and services from time to time. You have the opportunity to opt-out of receiving these marketing communications. We will automatically email you an invitation to receive marketing communications from us and at this time you can choose to receive them, or disregard the email which will mean that you will not be opted-in to receive email communications.

**Competitions**

STA may run competitions where subscribing to email marketing is a condition of entry. You can unsubscribe to these communications using the link in the email at any time.

**Job openings**

If you have consented to such communications, we may also send you information about our job openings that may be of interest to you and/or inform you about important changes or developments to our services.

## 6\. Sensitive Personal Information

If you wish, you may provide us with some special categories of Personal Information in order for us to provide you with a better standard of service. For example, when booking a flight or holiday with us you may provide us with information about your dietary or medical requirements, which may reveal details about your mental or physical health or condition. The provision of this information is entirely voluntary. If you do not consent to our processing of this type of Personal Information, we may be unable to provide you with certain goods and/or services that you wish to book.

## 7\. Your rights

You are entitled to know what Personal Information we hold about you and how that information is processed. If you would like a copy of the Personal Information we hold about you, please contact us via this form. 

If you change your mind and decide you do not wish to receive communications from STA Travel (including our marketing and Checkout Assistance communications), you can unsubscribe by clicking on the 'unsubscribe' link at the bottom of any emails you receive from us.If you have previously agreed to STA Travel sharing your Personal Information with third parties for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by using the unsubscribe option in the relevant communication or contacting the third party directly.

You are entitled to know what Personal Information we hold about you and how that information is processed. If you would like a copy of the Personal Information we hold about you, please contact us via **[this form](https://forms-customercare.statravel.com/?division=uk#/customer_care)**.

You have the right to request that we correct any Personal Information that we are holding about you that is incorrect or incomplete.

You also have the right to ask us to erase or stop processing any Personal Information we have about you where there is no longer a legal ground for us to hold it and, in some circumstances, you have the right to request that we transfer any information we hold about you to a third party. 

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us as soon as possible via **[this form](https://forms-customercare.statravel.com/?division=uk#/customer_care)**. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

You may also have similar rights with our third-party partners and you should consult their privacy policies and/or contact them for further information (e.g. airlines with whom you have booked a flight).

## 8\. How long we retain your Personal Information

We will only retain your Personal Information for so long as is permitted by the Data Protection Legislation.

## 9\. Third Parties

We may share your Personal Information with third parties where it is necessary (i) for the performance of the services you have requested or booked, (ii) for us to comply with our legal obligations or (iii) for our legitimate business interests. 

Some of the services on our Website and mobile apps, are delivered or served by third party companies, which may collect information about your use of the services. For example, where you have booked flights with us for a third-party airline, we will need to share your Personal Information with the relevant airline and where this is the case, they shall be the data controller over such information. These third parties may also place or recognise cookies, web beacons or other technology to track your behaviour and we advise you to read their privacy policy as to how they will process your data. For more information about cookies please see our **[Cookies Policy](https://www.statravel.co.uk/cookies-policy.htm)**.

We run promotions with third parties at specific times of the year - however, we will not share your data with these third parties unless you choose to opt-in via the form for that specific promotion - this will be made very clear.

Third parties advertise on our Website and in our newsletter, however your data is kept on our records only, no other company will be given this data by STA Travel unless it is necessary to perform the services you have requested, or you have given your explicit consent to such a transfer. We ensure that we manage and process all data in accordance with the principles laid down by the Data Protection Legislation.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. STA Travel is partnered with Google regarding ad serving but also works with several other advertising partners. These companies may use your Personal Information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits, to enhance user experience, offer a greater variety of content and provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. [This may include the use of cookies. For more information about cookies please see our **[Cookies Policy](https://www.statravel.co.uk/cookies-policy.htm)** ].

If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to not having this information used by these companies, visit: <https://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>.

In exceptional circumstance, if we are sold or merged with another company we may disclose your information to a potential buyer, including your Personal Information and other information concerning your relationship with us, so that they can continue to provide the services you have requested.

Data Protection Notice: Your personal data will be processed in accordance with the applicable carrier’s privacy policy and, if your booking is made via a reservation system provider (“GDS”), with its privacy policy. These are available at [https://www.iatatravelcenter.com/privacy](https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/uYF9C0R1nsJpoY1tW9yQJ?domain=iatatravelcenter.com) or from the carrier or GDS directly. You should read this documentation, which applies to your booking and specifies, for example, how your personal data is collected, stored, used, disclosed and transferred. (applicable for interline carriage).

## 10\. Cookies

For more information on our use of cookies, please see our [**Cookies Policy**](https://www.statravel.co.uk/cookies-policy.htm).

## 11\. Links

Links from our site to external websites do not mean we endorse these websites. We advise you to read the privacy policy applicable to each third-party site you visit and we will not accept any responsibility for or liability in respect of either the contents or your use of these third party sites.

## 12\. Security

At STA Travel, payment security is of paramount importance. To give you confidence, our online booking service uses industry-standard encryption technology to ensure that your credit or debit card transaction is secure. 

Please note, however, that the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure and, although we will take steps to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee the security of your Personal Information transmitted via the Website – any transmission is therefore at your own risk.

## 13\. Transfers of your Personal Information outside the EEA

The Personal Information you provide to us will be transferred to and stored on our servers in the European Economic Area (" **EEA** ") and we take steps to protect your Personal Information from unauthorised access and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage..

In processing your Personal Information, it may be necessary for us to transfer your Personal Information outside the EEA. It may also be accessed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers or group companies. This includes staff engaged in, among other things, the provision of support services. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your Personal Information is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy and the Data Protection Legislation when it is processed in, or otherwise accessed from, a location outside the EEA. This means that we will only transfer your Personal Information to third parties outside the EEA in accordance with the Data Protection Legislation. For the avoidance of doubt, in the event that the UK is no longer a part of the EEA, references in this paragraph to the EEA shall mean the EEA and the UK.

By submitting your Personal Information to us, you acknowledge this transfer, storing or processing of your Personal Information.

## 14\. Complaints

Should you have any queries or complaints in relation to how we use your Personal Information, please contact us via **[this form](https://forms-customercare.statravel.com/?division=uk#/customer_care)**. Should you wish to take any complaints or queries further, you have the right to contact the Information Commissioner's Office regarding such issues.

## 15\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on our Website and, where appropriate, notified to you when you next access our Website, book a holiday or flight with us or otherwise request services from us. It is your responsibility to ensure that you are aware of the latest version of this Privacy Policy and by continuing to use our Website, request services from us or otherwise engage with us, you will be deemed to have accepted any revised terms.

## 16\. Contact us

If you have any questions, please feel free to contact us via **[this form](https://forms-customercare.statravel.com/?division=uk#/customer_care).**
